var req = [
    {
        'question': 'Which Kinesis stream is used for  Real-time data capture '
        , 'optiona': 'Kinesis Data Streams',
        'optionb': 'Kinesis Data Firehose',
        'optionc': ' Kinesis Data Analytics',
        'optiond': 'Kinesis video Streams',
        'answer': 'a',
        'info': '  '

    },
    {
        'question': 'Which Kinesis stream is used to Load real-time data   ',
        'optiona': 'Kinesis Data Streams',
        'optionb': 'Kinesis Data Firehose',
        'optionc': ' Kinesis Data Analytics',
        'optiond': 'Kinesis video Streams',
        'answer': 'b',
        'info': '  '
    },
    {
        'question': 'Which Kinesis stream is used to Get insights in real time ',
        'optiona': 'Kinesis Data Streams',
        'optionb': 'Kinesis Data Firehose',
        'optionc': ' Kinesis Data Analytics',
        'optiond': 'Kinesis video Streams',
        'answer': 'c',
        'info': '  '
    },
    {
        'question': 'Which Kinesis stream is used to Ingest and store data streams from hundreds of thousands of data sources ',
        'optiona': 'Kinesis Data Streams',
        'optionb': 'Kinesis Data Firehose',
        'optionc': ' Kinesis Data Analytics',
        'optiond': 'Kinesis video Streams',
        'answer': 'a',
        'info': '  '
    }
    ,
    {
        'question': 'Which Kinesis stream is used to Load streaming data into data lakes, data stores, and analytics tools ',
        'optiona': 'Kinesis Data Streams',
        'optionb': 'Kinesis Data Firehose',
        'optionc': ' Kinesis Data Analytics',
        'optiond': 'Kinesis video Streams',
        'answer': 'b',
        'info': '  '
    },
    {
        'question': 'Which Kinesis stream is used to Analyze streaming data and gain actionable insights in real time',
        'optiona': 'Kinesis Data Streams',
        'optionb': 'Kinesis Data Firehose',
        'optionc': ' Kinesis Data Analytics',
        'optiond': 'Kinesis video Streams',
        'answer': 'c',
        'info': '  '
    },
    {
        'question': 'Which one is an example of consumer ',
        'optiona': ' a custom application running on Amazon EC2',
        'optionb': ' Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose delivery stream ',
        'optionc': ' Both ',
        'optiond': ' None',
        'answer': 'c',
        'info': '  '
    },
    {
        'question': 'Consumer can store their results using an AWS service ',
        'optiona': 'Amazon DynamoDB',
        'optionb': ' Amazon Redshift ',
        'optionc': ' Amazon S3 ',
        'optiond': ' All',
        'answer': 'd',
        'info': ' '
    } ,
    {
        'question': 'What is Kinesis data stream ',
        'optiona': 'composed of a sequence number, a partition key, and a data blob, which is an immutable sequence of bytes',
        'optionb': ' a uniquely identified sequence of data records in a stream ',
        'optionc': ' used to group data by shard within a stream ',
        'optiond': ' a set of shards',
        'answer': 'd',
        'info': ' '
    } ,
    {
        'question': 'What is AWS Glue '
        , 'optiona': ' ETL Extract Transform Load Service that makes it easy for customers to prepare and load their data for analytics ',
        'optionb': ' Data Catolog ',
        'optionc': ' Step Function ',
        'optiond': ' None ',
        'answer': 'b',
        'info': '   '

    },
    {
        'question': '  A _________ is the base throughput unit of an Amazon Kinesis data stream',
        'optiona': 'Partition key',
        'optionb': ' Sequence number ',
        'optionc': ' shard ',
        'optiond': 'None',
        'answer': 'c',
        'info': ' A shard is the base throughput unit of an Amazon Kinesis data stream. <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/kinesis/data-streams/getting-started/">here </a> '  
    } ,
    {
        'question': 'Which service makes it easy to manage SSO access to multiple AWS accounts and business applications ',
        'optiona': 'Secrets Manager',
        'optionb': ' Amazon GuardDuty ',
        'optionc': ' AWS SSO ',
        'optiond': 'AWS Security Hub',
        'answer': 'c',
        'info': ' '
    },
    {
        'question': 'Which service  is a continuous security monitoring and threat detection service that incorporates threat intelligence, anomaly detection, and machine learning to help protect your AWS resources, including your AWS accounts',
        'optiona': 'Secrets Manager',
        'optionb': ' Amazon GuardDuty ',
        'optionc': ' AWS SSO ',
        'optiond': 'AWS Security Hub',
        'answer': 'b',
        'info': ' '
    } ,
    {
        'question': 'Which service  is used if you own high visibility websites or are otherwise prone to frequent DDoS attacks',
        'optiona': ' AWS WAF alone ',
        'optionb': ' Firewall Manager with AWS WAF ',
        'optionc': ' AWS Shield Advanced ',
        'optiond': 'None',
        'answer': 'c',
        'info': ' '
    } ,
    {
        'question': 'Which service  is optional layer of security for your VPC that acts as a firewall for controlling traffic in and out of one or more subnets',
        'optiona': ' NACL network access control list  ',
        'optionb': '  web access control list (web ACL)   ',
        'optionc': ' Both',
        'optiond': 'None',
        'answer': 'a',
        'info': ' '
    }
];

var title = "AWS Security"
